

Alexander Augusto S. Fernandes

Computer Engineer

Personal Information

My website alexanderaugusto.com

Phone (35) 98452-9203

Email

alexaasf1010@gmail.com

Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/alexanderaugusto

Skills

JavaScript

Java

Git

Relational Database

Docker

Kubernetes

N-Relational Database

Python

Machine Learning

Languages

English

Resume

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering with 3 years of experience in software development and digital skills. I have extensive knowledge in Spring Boot, Node JS, React, Relational Database, Kubernetes, Docker and Microservices in general.

Experience

04/2021 -Present

Systems Specialist II - Team Leader and Scrum Master

Inatel/Ericsson, MG

- **REST API**
- **Spring Boot**
- OSGI
- **JavaScript**
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- **Jenkins**
- Git
- Karate and JUnit for automated testing
- Agile Methodologies

01/2020 -04-2021

Full Stack Developer (Internship) Aurem Startup, MG

Database - Oracle and EDB

- RESTFUL API Node JS + Express
- Socket.IO
- MySQL, Postgres and MongoDB
- ReactJS and NextJS
- Figma
- Electron
- AWS
- Docker
- Git
- Agile Methodologies and Unit Tests

05/2019 -12/2019

Front End Developer (Internship) Fiscoserv Startup, MG

- React JS
- Dashboards
- Git
- Agile Methodologies

Education

03/2022 -Present

Application Development for Mobile Devices and Cloud Computing

National Institute of Telecommunications INATEL, MG

Computer Engineering

12/2021

01/2017 -

National Institute of Telecommunications INATEL, MG

Certifications

05/2021

Docker: Creating Containers without the headache Alura

Spring Boot REST API: API, Security, Cache,

05/2021

04/2021

04/2021

Monitoring, Profiles, Tests and Deploy

Alura

Alura

Tests: BDD with Cucumber and Mockito

Jax-RS and Jersey: Master the Creation of REST

Webservices

Alura

04/2021

Maven: Dependency management and java application

build

04/2021

Alura **Git and Github: Branching, Conflicts, and Pull Request**

Strategies

Alura

Design Patterns in Java: Good Programming Practices Alura

03/2021

04/2021

Intensive English Course

USK

08/2020

Behind The Code Marathon

IBM **Call For Code Hackathon**

IBM

07/2020

Interests

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning

Data Science